please relax your fingers pull in your
stomach just a little bit relax your
mouth relax your eyelids
try to release all the tension in your
forehead
and your heads
bring your chest out just a moment
little bit smile
and then please come to your breath
today let's just focus on long exhales
rather than counting some just um
[Music]
relaxing exhale
then place a scare with teacher hard
teacher to come and sit with you and it
should be very personal and pleasant
pleasant
they are I think rather than trying to
feel some sort of official respect for
them maybe just try to reach a feeling
of affection mutual affection like old
friends you've been to many things with
your heart teacher good times bad times
and they're just like a old pair of
jeans now comfortable
and there's a nice fragrance from them
like summer day or something like
and your mind just praise them for
something beautiful about how they act
or how they treat people
then offer them a small gift I think it
would be nice to offer a single simple
goods art that you had yesterday during
the whole day just a small but sincere
and good thought you had maybe about
somebody else
then open up and be honest about
something you've done recently that
wasn't very nice some smoking
and ask your teacher to teach you
perhaps through the people who are here
during this retreat please teach me
through the dead words and the actions
of the people around me for this week
and please stay with me don't leave and
not just like this life but my future
life wherever I go out to do
and I can't think about the activities
you did last week at work and at home
[Music]
you had certain jobs to do at work
you're supposed to finish certain things
you have to accomplish certain things
think about some of them and at home you
have jobs to do around the house or
apartment with your family just think
about two or three and what you did last
me
I think for myself for example I was
working in my garden a lot because it's
time of year to do a lot of work in the
garden
everything's just waking up at work as
usual I was trying to do fundraising get
support for projects so for me I can say
Oh last week I I was trying to make my
garden beautiful and I was trying to
make sure that we had enough funds to do
different projects
didn't think about the steps you took to
get what you wanted in my case I ordered
some special fertilizer on Amazon and I
pulled out weeds around the house
outside and I tried to write a contract
or an agreement to help fund some of our
project
then try to sing whether those actions
worked did they work in my case did the
garden respond did more beautiful
flowers come does it look like the
sponsors will help did the action to
work that you took last week
then you can please ask your teacher to
come to your heart you know what to do
do it slowly
ask them to stay inside of you and
influence your thoughts words actions
today
then come to your breath 3 long exhales
don't open your eyes don't move yet
okay now you can open your biggest judge